# LUKE ESWORTHY

full-stack web developer

Motivated learner and recent graduate from Nashville Software School's full-stack web development program. Proven team player in past work experience and current group projects. Excited to bring creative and innovative ideas into a new job and continue to develop my skills as a web developer.

# **EDUCATION**

## Full-Stack Software Developer

• Nashville Software School | Apr 2020 -Sep 2020

# B.S. in Business Management w/ Concentration in Entrepreneurship

• University of Tennessee, Knoxville | 2010 - 2016

#### CONTACT



+1 615 477 1619



lukesworthy@gmail.com



https://github.com/LukeEsworthy



https://lukeesworthy.github.io/



# TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

#### Nashville Software School

Full-stack web development program | Apr 2020 - Sep 2020

- Learned and practiced writing Javascript, CSS, HTML, React, Python, and Django.
- Utilized GitHub to save code and work with others on a project at the same time
- Implemented CRUD functionality as well as authentication and authorization
- Adapted to working virtually with groups online. Lessons, meetings and group collaborations were all done through Zoom and other apps like Slack.
- Completed group projects to develop skills using various programming languages, planning the steps required to build an app, delegating responsibilities, maintaining accountability to team members, and completing work within the agreed schedule.

# **PROJECTS**

## Auto Focus Garage - front-end capstone

Built with React and utilizing an external API (Unsplash), Auto Focus Garage is an app for car enthusiasts and photographers to keep track of and share the cars they have seen. The app incorporates full CRUD functionality in addition to user authentication & authorization.



## Setlist Tracker - back-end capstone

Built with Django and SQL with the goal of helping DJs keep track of how popular songs are during their set by adding a rating to songs played at an event. Whether a professional DJ or the designated DJ on a road trip with friends, this app allows a user to register/log in, create an event, add songs and notes to it, and rate each song on a scale of 1-5.

https://github.com/LukeEsworthy/SetlistTrackerApp

## EXPERIENCE

### **Brentwood Wine & Spirits**

Retail Associate | Nov 2019 - Apr 2020

- Provided wide-ranging support to regular staff during the holiday season allowing for more efficient inventory management and effective customer service.
- Tripled my hours to step up after General Manager took unexpected leave and had to quickly learn duties outside of my original role, including working with vendors, training new team members including superiors, and preparing sales/financial reports for the corporate office.
- Other initiatives I took where I saw improvements could be made include updating and reorganizing inventory system, deep cleaning entire store space and general repairs throughout the building.

#### Kennedy Performance Center

Apprentice | Jul 2017 - Apr 2020

- Shadowed owner and head technician to become excellent mechanic and to learn everything about working on BMWs, from general maintenance and repairs to custom performance modifications
- Provided "pit crew" support to owner, traveling around the region to racing events, shows, etc.